Granville Hicks Papers
Granville Hicks Papers
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "'The Sacrifice,' by Adele Wiseman, a Good Novel About Jews in Canada." The New Leader, Sept. 17, 1956 (Box 78)
    - "A Sampling of Literary Reference Works Accumulated Over 20 Years." The New Leader, Aug. 27, 1956 (Box 78)
    - "Samuel Butler, Cautious Rebel." Signatures, Winter 1937-38 (Box 78)
    - "'The Sandcastle,' 'The Legacy' and Two Other, Less Memorable Novels." The New Leader, May 27, 1957 (Box 78)
    - "Search For Meaning." The New Leader, June 16, 1952 (Box 78)
    - "Second Judgement: Reflections of a Reviewer." Contempo, Jan. 1, 1932 (Box 78)
      See also Oversize material: Contempo: a Review of Books and Personalities Jan. 1, 1932 - vol. 1, no. 15.
    - "Setting the Record Straight on an Episode in the Red Decade." The New Leader, June 15, 1953 (Box 78)
    - "The Shape of Postwar Literature." The English Journal, May 1944 (Box 78)
    - "The Shortcomings of Liberalsim." The New Leader, Aug. 19, 1950 (Box 78)
    - "Signatures to the Significance of the Self." American Journal, Mar. 1965 (Box 78)
    - "Sinclair Lewis and the Good Life." The English Journal, Apr. 1936 (Box 78)
    - "Singer Billie Holiday Writes of Jazz, Addiction, and the Negro in America." The New Leader, July 30, 1956 (Box 78)
    - "The Small-Town Library." The Bookmark, Feb. 1952 (Box 78)
    - "The Small Town Ministry." The Christian Leader, Apr. 5, 1947 (Box 78)
    - "The Social Criticism of John Ruskin." International Literature, Feb. 1938 (Box 78)
    - "The Social Interpretation of Literature." Progressive Education, Jan./Feb. 1934 (Box 78)
    - "'Some Corner of an English Field,' the Second Novel of Dannie Abse." The New Leader, Jan. 28, 1957 (Box 78)
    - "Some Literary Detective Work on Faulkner's Yoknapatawpha Saga." The New Leader, Nov. 19, 1951 (Box 78)
    - "Some Literary Fallacies." College English, Nov. 1944 (Box 78)
    - "The Spectre That Haunts the World." Harper's Magazine, 1946? (Box 78)
    - "The State of Literary Journalism: Is the Serious Novel Expendable?" The New Leader, Dec. 10, 1956 (Box 78)
    - "The Survival of Upton Sinclair." The English Journal, Jan. 1943 (Box 78)
    - "That's Their Story." The New Masses column written by Granville Hicks under the pseudonym Margaret Wright Mather. (Box 78)
    - "Themes in Contemporary American Fiction." America Illustrated, no. 56, 1961 (Box 78)
    - "Thirty Years Later: Memories of the First American Writers' Congress." The American Scholar, Summer 1966 (Box 78)
    - "Thoughts in a Small-Town Library." The American Scholar, 1955? (Box 78)
    - "Three Men of Letters." The Sewanee Review, 1951? (Box 78)
    - "Three New Historical Books Discuss Traitors, Tycoons and Vermonters." The New Leader, Dec. 28, 1953 (Box 78)
    - "Three New Novels About Negroes Which Transcend the Old Formulas." The New Leader, Mar. 1, 1954 (Box 78)
    - "Three New Novels by Oakley Hall, Millen Brand and Ivy Compton-Burnett." The New Leader, Apr. 11, 1955 (Box 78)
    - "Three Novels on Connecticut Living, Juvenile Murder, Menhaden Fishing." The New Leader, Sept. 6, 1954 (Box 78)
    - "Three Novels Touch on the Problem of Rootlessness in Modern Society." The New Leader, Nov. 1, 1954 (Box 78)
    - "Toynbee's 'Study of History' Concludes with the Future Still a Question Mark." The New Leader, Oct. 18, 1954 (Box 78)
    - "The Tragedy of a Sturdy Country Woman Displaced to an Alien World." The New Leader, Apr. 26, 1954 (Box 78)
    - "The Twenties in American Literature." The Nation, Feb. 12, 1930 (Box 78)
    - "Two New Anti-Utopian Novels Reveal Same Motives as the Old Utopias." The New Leader, Feb. 16, 1953 (Box 78)
    - "Two New Novels by Joyce Cary and a Neglected British Author." The New Leader, Nov. 16, 1953 (Box 78)
    - "Two New Novels of Life's Mystery by Wright Morris and Saul Bellow." The New Leader, Sept. 21, 1953 (Box 78)
    - "Two Novels About Youth and Age by Jessamyn West and Eudora Welty." The New Leader, Jan. 11, 1954 (Box 78)
    - "2 Novels: Ernst Pawel's 'From the Dark Tower and Burt Cole's 'Subi.'" The New Leader, July 17, 1957 (Box 78)
    - "Two Novels on Political Themes by Don M. Mankiewicz and C.P. Snow." The New Leader, Jan. 17, 1955 (Box 78)
    - "Two Serious Novels on the Old West by Jackson Burgess, Conrad Richter." The New Leader, July 29, 1957 (Box 79)
    - "Upton Sinclair on Christ." The New Leader, Nov. 10, 1952 (Box 79)
    - "Value of Congress' Red Probes Today Questioned." Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, Apr. 13, 1953 (Box 79)
    - "War, Always a Challenge to Writers, Inspires German, British, U.S. Novels." The New Leader, Apr. 23, 1956 (Box 79)
    - "Was Thomas Hardy a Pessimist?" The Educational Forum, Nov. 1937 (Box 79)
    - "The Way of a Red General." The New Leader, July 28, 1952 (Box 79)
    - "When Dickens Met Channing." The Christian Register, July 18, 1929 (Box 79)
    - "When Lyman Beecher Attacked Boston Unitarians." The Christian Register, Aug. 8, 1929 (Box 79)
    - "White Collar or Straitjacket?" The New Leader, Jan. 28, 1952 (Box 79)
    - "Whittaker Chambers's Testament." The New Leader, May 26, 1952 (Box 79)
    - "Why We Want the World to Have Universalism." Onward, 1918? (Box 79)
    - "Women Novelists Describe the Effects of a Trial and of Old Love Letters." The New Leader, Feb. 14, 1955 (Box 79)
    - "A Work to Live With - The Letters of Justice Holmes and Harold Laski." The New Leader, Mar. 23, 1953 (Box 79)
    - "The World of Hemingway." The New Freeman, Mar. 22, 1930 (Box 79)
    - "Would You Rather Live in a Small Town or a Big City?" Town Meeting, Dec. 26, 1946 (Box 79)
    - "Wright Morris's New Novel Contrasts the World of the '20s and the '50s." The New Leader, Oct. 4, 1954 (Box 79)
    - "Writers and Teaching." Tomorrow, 1947? (Box 79)
  - Books
    - "Wyndham Lewis and Lin Yutang Mix Politics and Literature - Unsuccessfully." The New Leader, May 30, 1955 (Box 79)
    - Figures of Transition
      - Acknowledgments (Box 79)
      - Index of names (Box 79)
      - Miscellany (Box 79)
    - Granville Hicks in the New Masses
      - Editor's Introduction, draft I (Box 79)
      - Editor's Introduction, draft II (Box 79)
      - Statement by Granville Hicks in 1973, draft (Box 79)
      - Editor's notes Chapters I-X, draft (Box 79)
      - Editor's notes Chapter I-X (Box 79)
      - Table of contents, draft I (Box 79)
      - Table of contents, draft II (Box 79)
      - Index (Box 79)
      - Miscellany (Box 79)
    - The Great Tradition (Quadrangle Books), 1969
      - Foreword, drafts (Box 79)
      - Afterword, drafts (Box 79)
    - John Reed: the Making of a Revolutionary
      - Louise Bryant
        - "Christmas in Petrograd 1917"
          - Research copy (Box 80)
          - Extra photocopy (Box 80)
          - Chapter I (Box 80)
          - Chapter II pp.1-5 (Box 80)
          - Chapter II pp.6-10 (Box 80)
          - Chapter II pp.11-20 (Box 80)
          - Chapter II pp.21-30 (Box 80)
          - Chapter II pp.31-40 (Box 80)
          - Chapter II pp.41-48 (Box 80)
        - Catalog of Louise Bryant Collection (Box 80)
        - Correspondence, 1932-1935; undated; notes (Box 80)
      - Reed letters to friends (Box 80)
      - Lincoln Steffens letters to John Reed (Box 80)
      - Margaret Green Reed letter to Lincoln Steffens, Apr. 24, 1932 (Box 80)
      - Miscellaneous letters to John Reed (Box 80)
      - Speeches delivered by Reed, Williams and Reinstein at Third All-Soviet Congress, Jan. 1918 (Box 80)
      - "Across the War World" (Box 80)
      - "Almost Thirty" The New Republic, Apr. 15, 1936 (Box 80)
      - "Aspects of the Russian Revolution" The Revolutionary Age, July 12, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "The Background of Bolshevism" The Revolutionary Age, Jan. 25, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "Bolshevism in America" The Revolutionary Age, Dec. 18, 1918 (Box 80)
      - "The Case for the Bolsheviki" The Independent, July 13, 1918 (Box 80)
      - "The Causes Behind Mexico's Revolution" The New York Times, Apr. 27, 1914 (Box 80)
      - "The Constituent Assembly in Russia" The Revolutionary Age, Nov. 30, 1918 (Box 80)
      - "Doctor Rakovsky" The Revolutionary Age, Jan. 25, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "El Paso" (Box 80)
      - "Germany Has Shot Her Bolt; War to End in 1916, Says Reed" The World, Dec. 26, 1915 (Box 80)
      - "Hooray for the Constitution" The Voice of Labor, Sept. 15, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "The I.W.W. and Bolshevism" The New York Communist, May 31, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "In Short" (Box 80)
      - "The Jews on the Eastern Front" Book of the Exile, Mar. 1916 (Box 80)
      - "Karl Liebknecht's Words" The Revolutionary Age, Feb. 1, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "Labor is Not a Commodity" The Revolutionary Age, July 5, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "Liar or Just Doesn't Know?" The Revolutionary Age, Aug. 9, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "Liebknecht Dead" The Liberator, Mar. 1919 (Box 80)
      - "A New Appeal" The Revolutionary Age, Jan. 18, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "On Bolshevism, Russian and American" The Revolutionary Age, Apr. 12, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "The Origins of Worker's Control of Industry in Russia" The Revolutionary Age, Nov. 23, 1918 (Box 80)
      - "Red Russia - Entrance" (Box 80)
      - "Rule Britannia!" The Virginia Quarterly (Box 80)
      - "The Russian Peace" The Masses, 1917 (Box 80)
      - "Scandinavia in Wartime" (Box 80)
      - "Scratch a Russian" (Box 80)
      - "They Are Still There" The Revolutionary Age, Dec. 11, 1918 (Box 80)
      - "What About Mexico?" The Masses, June 1914 (Box 80)
      - "What's the Trouble With America?" The Voice of Labor, Oct. 15, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "A White New Year" The Revolutionary Age, Jan. 4, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "Why Political Democracy Must Go" The New York Communist, May 8, 1919 - June 14, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "Worker's Control in America" The Revolutionary Age, Mar. 15, 1919 (Box 80)
      - "The World Congress of the Communist International" The Communist, no. 10 (Box 80)
        See also Oversize material: The Communist, no. 10.
      - Insurgent Mexico, Reviews (Box 80)
      - Ten Days That Shook the World, Reviews (Box 80)
      - Ten Days That Shook the World, 1935; Introduction by Granville Hicks for first Modern Library edition (Box 80)
      - Ten Days That Shook the World, 1967; Introduction by Granville Hicks to New American edition (Box 80)
      - The War in Eastern Europe, 1916; Reviews
      - Letters from John Reed to various publications (Box 81)
      - Russia, Liberator pamphlet no. 4; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
      - The Sisson Documents, Liberator pamphlet no. 2; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
      - Bercovici, Konrad. The Crimes of Charity., 1917; Introduction by John Reed (Box 81)
      - John Reed - clippings about (Box 81)
      - Photographs (Box 81)
      - Reed, John. Freedom., G. Hicks notes (Box 81)
      - Reed genealogy (Box 81)
      - Reed boyhood, 1904-1906 (Box 81)
      - Reed at Harvard College, 1906-1910 (Box 81)
      - Chronology of events of Mexico's revolution, Nov. 1913 - Apr. 1914 (Box 81)
      - John Reed - Book notes on Mexico (Box 81)
      - List of John Reed articles in Metropolitan (Box 81)
      - Chronology of World War I, June 1914 - Feb. 1915 (Box 81)
      - Chronology of events in Russia during Reed's stay, Sept. 1917 - April 1918 (Box 81)
      - Extracts from Bessie Beatty's The Red Heart of Russia, background notes on Russian Revolution (Box 81)
      - President Wilson's War Address to Congress and Proclamation, 1917 (Box 81)
      - The Masses conspiracy trial - John Reed indictment The New York Times, April 29-30, 1918 (Box 81)
      - The Masses conspiracy trial, 1918; Testimony of John Silas Reed (Box 81)
      - The Masses conspiracy trial, Account from Charles Recht's autobiography (Box 81)
      - Philadelphia trial, 1919; Testimony of John Reed (Box 81)
      - The Red Album - May Day 1921, Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to
      - Reed obituaries, eulogies, tributes, 1920-1921 (Box 81)
      - Rubin, Jacob H. I Live to Tell, John Reed's disillusionment (Box 81)
      - Articles about John Reed (Box 81)
      - Russian articles about John Reed (Box 81)
      - Moscow Daily News (Charniak) (Box 81)
      - John Reed - Interviews
        - with Bessie Beatty (Box 81)
        - with Fred Sumner Boyd (Box 81)
        - with M. Eleanor Fitzgerald, Jan. 14, 1935 (Box 81)
        - with Waldo Frank, Jan. 16, 1935 (Box 81)
        - with John Kelley, April 16, 1935 (Box 81)
        - with Nicholas Kelley, Jan. 8, 1935 (Box 81)
        - John Reed - Interview with Dr. Herman Lorber, June 10, 1935 (Box 81)
        - with Jeannette D. Pearl, Jan. 18, 1935 (Box 81)
        - with Ernest Poole, Jan. 7, 1935 (Box 81)
        - with Frank Shay, May 16, 1935 (Box 81)
        - with Thomas Steep (Box 81)
        - with Ida Tarbell (Box 81)
        - with Mary Heaton Vorse (Box 81)
        - with Mrs. Marie Page Tomsett, May 15, 1935 (Box 81)
      - John Reed - Talk between Corliss Lamont and Alex Gumberg, Nov. 13, 1934 (Box 81)
      - Reminiscences about Reed A - P (Box 81)
      - Reminiscences about Reed R - Z (Box 81)
      - John Reed chronology, notes (Box 81)
      - References to John Reed in books, notes (Box 81)
      - Pre-publication correspondence, Jan. 1933 - Mar. 1936; undated; 9 folders (Box 82)
      - Post-publication correspondence, 1936-1974; 4 folders (Box 82)
      - Stuart manuscript Chapter III (Box 83)
      - Stuart manuscript Chapter IV (Box 83)
      - Stuart manuscript Chapter V? (Box 83)
      - Stuart manuscript Chapter VI (fragment) (Box 83)
      - Granville Hicks - John Stuart correspondence, 1934 (Box 83)
      - Granville Hicks - John Stuart correspondence, 1935 (Box 83)
      - Granville Hicks - John Stuart correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 83)
      - Granville Hicks - John Stuart correspondence, undated (Box 83)
      - John Reed, Stuart comments on Hicks manuscript (Box 83)
      - John Reed dramatization (author unknown) (Box 83)
      - John Reed miscellany (Box 83)
      - The Education of John Reed: selected writings
        - Introduction (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter I (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter II (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter III (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter IV (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter V (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter VI (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter VII (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter VIII (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter IX (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter X (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter XI (draft) (Box 83)
        - Chapter XII (draft) (Box 83)
      - John Reed memorabilia
        - Address book, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Address book (fragment), photocopy (Box 84)
        - Armband "Keep out of War", photocopy (Box 84)
        - Bank transactions - miscellaneous, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Bankbook - First National Bank Croton-on-Hudson, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Behind a Watteau Picture by Robert Emmon Rogers Presentation copy, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Bookmark designed for John Reed by Louise Bryant, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Calling cards - John Reed's, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Calling cards (various), photocopy (Box 84)
        - Caricatures, drawings (unsigned) found in presentation folder as souvenir of Dutch Treat Club, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Checkbook - Fifth Avenue Bank of New York, 1918; Photocopy (Box 84)
        - Checkbooks; (1), (2), 1916-1917; 1919; photocopy (Box 84)
        - Delegate's button, Communist International Party, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Drawing by John Reed - age 8, photocopy (Box 84)
        - George's Mother by Stephen Crane (incomplete) annotated by John Reed, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Inscription copied from Bermuda tomb, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Itinerary - English trip, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Letter of credit, Equitable Trust Company of New York, Aug. 1917; photocopy (Box 84)
        - Manuscript submission records, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Maps of France and Russia, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Presentation mount to Boris Reinstein from John Reed, 1920; photocopy (Box 84)
        - Press pass for Louise Bryant for entrance into Duma, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Press passes for Reed and Art Young, Women's Party Convention, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Proposed seal for Communist Labor Party of America, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Roumanian bank certificate, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Russian railway ticket, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Sketch by Boardman Robinson "Porters - Saloniki", photocopy (Box 84)
        - Stationery of Bureau of Revolutionary Propaganda, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Swedish official document, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Theatre ticket, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Ticket stubs (transportation), admission tickets, photocopy (Box 84)
        - Wallet (snakeskin) marked C.J.R. (photocopy), 1892; 2nd unmarked wallet black leather (not shown) (Box 84)
      - John Reed printed material
        See also various items in Oversize 1.
        - Upton Sinclair's vol. 1, no. 4, Aug. 1918 (Box 84)
        - The Voice of Labor, volume 1, no's 2, 4 and 6, Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate these items.
        - Startsev, Abel Isaakovich. Russkie bloknoty Dzhona Rida, 1977 (Box 84)
        - Zurier, Rebecca. Art for The Masses: a Radical Magazine and Its Graphics, 1985; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate these items.
        - "Art for The Masses" exhibition announcements, postcards (Box 84)
          See also Oversize material: Poster for exhibit "Art for The Masses".
        - The Complete Poetry of John Reed, edited by Jack Alan Robbins, introduction by Granville Hicks, memoir and sonnet by Max Eastman, typescript in two parts; 2 folders (Box 84)
        - The Complete Poetry of John Reed, 1983 (Box 84)
    - The Letters of Lincoln Steffens, Introductory notes Chapters I - XI (Box 85)
    - Literary Horizons: a Quarter Century of American Fiction
      See also Correspondence-Subject files: Literary Horizons, pre-publication miscellany; Printed material: Book review, books by Hicks: Literary Horizons; Unrevised galleys, proofs and review copies: Hicks, Granville. Literary horizons.
      - Notes
        - Introduction (Box 85)
        - Wright Morris (Box 85)
        - Saul Bellow (Box 85)
        - Bernard Malamud (Box 85)
        - James Baldwin (Box 85)
        - John Updike (Box 85)
        - Flannery O'Connor (Box 85)
        - Herbert Gold (Box 85)
        - Kurt Vonnegut (Box 85)
        - Louis Auchincloss (Box 85)
        - Vladimir Nabokov (Box 85)
        - Joseph Heller (Box 85)
        - Reynolds Price (Box 85)
        - Philip Roth (Box 85)
        - John Barth (Box 85)
        - Norman Mailer (Box 85)
      - original manuscript, 16 folders (Box 85)
    - The Living Novel
      - Foreword, draft (Box 86)
      - Notes on the contributors, draft (Box 86)
      - Afterword: The Enemies of the Novel, draft (Box 86)
    - Part of the Truth
      - Chapters I - XVIII, draft (Box 86)
      - Chapters I - XVIII, first revision (Box 86)
      - Chapters I - XVIII, second revision (Box 87)
      - Chapters I - VIII, final revision (Box 87)
      - Chapters IX - XVIII, final revision (Box 88)
      - Index of Names (Box 88)
      - Deletions Chapters I - III (Box 88)
      - Deletions Chapters XVII - XVIII (Box 88)
    - Study of William Ellery Channing
      - Notes, card catalog, 1 box (Oversize 3)
    - Where We Came Out
      - Partial draft
        - Prologue (Box 88)
        - Chapters I - XI, XVI (Box 88)
        - "What I Don't Believe" (Box 88)
        - "The Way We Live Now" (Box 88)
        - "The End of an Era" (Box 88)
        - "A Note for the Neighbors" (Box 88)
  - [Christmas messages]
    - [General], 1944-1964; undated; 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Grafton Defender
    - Grafton Defender, volumes 1-15, Mar. 1942 - Mar. 1957; 15 folders; Transferred to Rare Books for separate cataloging; please refer to (Box 89)
  - Journals
    - Aug. 15, 1942 - July 8, 1965, pp. 1-1478; 18 folders (Box 90)
    - July 12, 1965 - Jan. 21, 1973, pp. 1479-1663 and 5 un-numbered diaries; 7 folders (Box 91)
    - Jan. 22, 1973 - Apr. 23, 1973, 1 folder (Box 92)
    - undated fragments, 2 folders (Box 92)
    - miscellany, 1 folder (Box 92)
  - Lectures
    - "American Literature and American Life", Aug. 12, 1957; Bennington College (Box 93)
    - "The Anatomy of the Best Seller" (Box 93)
    - "A Bad Time", 1968; University of Notre Dame symposium (Box 93)
    - "The Burden on the Schools" (Box 93)
    - "The Changing Novel", Oct. 25, 1969; Otto Rank Association (Box 93)
    - "Communism: The God That Failed" (Box 93)
    - "Contemporary Fiction in High School English", Oct. 7, 1966; Albany (Box 93)
    - "The Contemporary Novel and the Contemporary Scene" (Box 93)
    - "The Cult of Violence" (Box 93)
    - "Freedom and Fear" (Box 93)
    - "Hemingway In Our Time" (Box 93)
    - "The Hiss Case" (Box 93)
    - "Jewish Writers and Contemporary Fiction" (Box 93)
    - "Karl Marx" (Box 93)
    - "Liberalism, Radicalism and the Future" (Box 93)
    - "Life and Literature" (Box 93)
    - "Lincoln Steffens and John Reed" (Box 93)
    - "Men, Machines, and the Meaning of Literature" (Box 93)
    - "The New Left" (Box 93)
    - "New Voices", Oct. 9, 1938; Community Church of Boston (Box 93)
    - "The Novel in America" (Box 93)
    - "The Novel in America Since 1945" (Box 93)
    - "The Novelist in Contemporary America" (Box 93)
    - "Our Greatest Living Novelist" (Box 93)
    - "Our Searching Novelists", March 5, 1961; Unitarian Church of Princeton (Box 93)
    - Pacific Northwest Writers' Conference, outline of lectures (Box 93)
    - Pacific Northwest Writers' Conference, lecture no. 1 (Box 93)
    - Pacific Northwest Writers' Conference, lecture no. 2 (Box 93)
    - Pacific Northwest Writers' Conference, lecture no. 3 (Box 93)
    - Pacific Northwest Writers' Conference, lecture no. 4 (Box 93)
    - Pacific Northwest Writers' Conference, lecture no. 5 (Box 93)
    - Part of the Truth - lecture before Friends of the Albany Library, October 19, 1965 (Box 93)
    - "Patterns of Contemporary Fiction", July 13, 1959; Middlebury College (Box 93)
    - "Patterns of Modern Fiction" (Box 93)
    - "Problems of the Contemporary Novelist", Aug. 26, 1957; Antioch College (Box 93)
    - "Publishing Business", May 2, 1957; Vassar College (Box 93)
    - "Recollections of the Thirties" (Box 93)
    - "Regional Literature" (Box 93)
    - "The Responsibilities of a Literary Critic" (Box 93)
    - "The Responsibilities of a Literary Journalist" (Box 93)
    - "The Return of Henry James" (Box 93)
    - Siena College Symposium on Ezra Pound and William Carlos Williams (Box 93)
    - "Small Town", Williams College (Box 93)
    - "The Small Town in a Big World" (Box 93)
    - "The Small Town in Fact and Fiction" (Box 93)
    - "Social Reforms in Russia" (Box 93)
    - "The State of the Novel" (Box 93)
    - "Student Behavior at the College Level" (Box 93)
    - "The Thirties" (Box 93)
    - "Thoughts on the Best-Seller List" (Box 93)
    - "Three Americans: Dos Passos, Faulkner, Hemingway" (Box 93)
    - "Three Romantics" (Box 93)
    - "What Are Our Novelists Looking For?" (Box 93)
    - "What is an American?" (Box 93)
    - "What Writers Are Like" (Box 93)
    - "Witness" (by Whittaker Chambers) (Box 93)
    - "Writers in a Revolutionary Age" (Box 93)
    - "Writers in the Thirties" (Box 93)
    - "Yes and No" (Box 93)
    - Untitled, alphabetical by subject
      - American fiction [I] (Box 94)
      - American fiction [II] (Box 94)
      - Arnold Toynbee (Box 94)
      - Censorship in libraries (Box 94)
      - Communist Party (Box 94)